# JAMES CHIGOZIE ODUFU

 $+234~806-449-7094 \diamond jamezjaz@gmail.com \diamond LinkedIn \diamond GitHub \diamond Hackernoon \diamond Medium \diamond Portfolio \diamond Lagos, Nigeria$ 

#### **SUMMARY**

Vision-driven software professional with 1+ years of full-stack software development skills in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux. Strongly focusing on delivering actionable and exceptional results. Seeking full-time software development opportunity to utilize my skills and abilities in a value-driven company that offers professional growth.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming** Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3

**Database** PostgreSQL, SQLite

**Technologies** Git, Postman, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, AWS S3, RSpec, Jest, React Testing Library, Linux

**Domains** Frontend Engineering, Software Development, REST APIs

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Microverse Remote

May 2020 - Present Mentor (Volunteer)

• Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.

• Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

## South Saharan Social Dev. Organization

Enugu, Nigeria Feb 2020 - Feb 2021 Data Entry Clerk

• Collects, stores, and utilizes data effective

• Prepares source data and compiles information whilst collecting scientific data and samples.

#### **Kizito Mobile Technologies**

Lagos, Nigeria

Manager

Nov 2016 - Feb 2018

• Solved software problems by providing necessary information, installed new software whilst working closely with hardware engineers.

### Community Secondary School, Nzashi

Mathematics/Biology Teacher

Ebonyi, Nigeria June 2015 - May 2016

• Integrated various forms of technology constantly to improve students' comprehension of various concepts.

## Stufflink Academy/Chris-Tech Computer School

Computer Operator

Enugu, Nigeria

Jan 2009 - Dec 2013

• Trained people on an array of software applications such as Appreciation, Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Publisher, Corel Draw, Internet Research, Photohop, Fireworks, Dream Weaver.

## PROJECTS

**Book-Air-Tickets** GitHub Link

- This is an application for booking airline tickets. Its back-end is an API built with Ruby on Rails.
- Built with Link: React, Redux, JavaScript, Axios, PropTypes, Redux-thunk, Bootstrap, Rails API.

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Software Development Program, Microverse (Remote)

Feb 2020 - May 2021

Diploma, Web Design & Development, New Horizons (Lagos, Nigeria)

Mar 2017 - Sept 2017

BSc, Applied Microbiology, Enugu State University of Science & Technology (Enugu, Nigeria)

2010 - 2014